<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quant Finance on home</title>
    <link>https://stanleyrazor.github.io/portfolio-blog/tags/quant-finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quant Finance on home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stanleyrazor.github.io/portfolio-blog/tags/quant-finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning in Finance - EP. Chan</title>
      <link>https://stanleyrazor.github.io/portfolio-blog/posts/ml-in-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stanleyrazor.github.io/portfolio-blog/posts/ml-in-finance/</guid>
      <description>Ernest P. Chan on Financial Machine Learning Link to heading It is quite hard to apply ML in Finance, in order to get some value.
Simple linear models, and strategies (simplicity is in linear, parsimonious models), such as pairs trading using OLS to compute hedge ratios, and use bollinger bands to detect reversion to mean. Since more and more people, get in the game, there is [[Strategy decay]], making the strategies become less and less profitable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing and backtesting systematic trading strategies</title>
      <link>https://stanleyrazor.github.io/portfolio-blog/posts/developing-and-backtesting-quantitative-strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stanleyrazor.github.io/portfolio-blog/posts/developing-and-backtesting-quantitative-strategies/</guid>
      <description>Quantitative Trading Strategies: The WHAT, WHY and HOW. Link to heading ![[289175171_696414891451337_8400780716761382367_n.jpg]]
This is a summary of my notes from a paper by Brian G. Peterson on developing quantitative trading strategies, as well as from a youtube video on What is a QUANTITATIVE TRADING STRATEGY from Hudson &amp;amp; Thames.
References:
Best Practices in Research for Quantitative Equity Strategies by Joseph A. Carniglia, Frank J. Fabozzi, and Peter N. Kolm Developing &amp;amp; Backtesting Systematic Trading Strategies by Brian G.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chat with traders</title>
      <link>https://stanleyrazor.github.io/portfolio-blog/posts/chat-with-traders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stanleyrazor.github.io/portfolio-blog/posts/chat-with-traders/</guid>
      <description>Episode 52: How to develop quantitative trading strategies - Ernest P. Chan Link to heading Data in finance is sparse, as compared to other domains, e.g trading data of Daily frequency is limited in backtesting, hence you need market intuition. Intra-day trading, is useful since it presents many trading opportunity i.e. Trades are held for hours. Seperate asset classes, and even securities could demand different models. Run stocks in market neutral strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best practices in research for quantitative equity strategies</title>
      <link>https://stanleyrazor.github.io/portfolio-blog/posts/taxonomy-of-quant-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stanleyrazor.github.io/portfolio-blog/posts/taxonomy-of-quant-models/</guid>
      <description>Reference: BEST PRACTICES IN RESEARCH FOR QUANTITATIVE EQUITY STRATEGIES
Taxonomy is simply a classification of something.
Strategies differ in their motivation to trade, information used to trade,and the instrunments traded. Metrics such as: trading frequencies, and holding periods are functions of the investment theory underlying the strategy. Multifactor strategies: Models which invest in equities based on multiple characteristics that replicate how investors make decisions. Allocation strategies: Strategies which make decisions based on allocations to different variables eg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpha decay</title>
      <link>https://stanleyrazor.github.io/portfolio-blog/posts/strategy-decay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stanleyrazor.github.io/portfolio-blog/posts/strategy-decay/</guid>
      <description>Question: As a successful quant trader, do you constantly develop new trading strategies?
Answer: By Tom Costello
(https://www.quora.com/As-a-successful-quant-trader-do-you-constantly-develop-new-trading-strategies)
The short answer is “You had better if you want to keep working.” but I can add some color there.
There is something in ‘quant trading’ called the ‘system’ or ‘program’ lifecycle.
A true ‘quant trading program’ identifies systemic pricing inefficiency. But as you participate in that market and take a profit for yourself, the presence of your buy and sell orders makes the pricing more efficient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pricing efficiency and inefficiency</title>
      <link>https://stanleyrazor.github.io/portfolio-blog/posts/pricing-efficiency-and-inefficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stanleyrazor.github.io/portfolio-blog/posts/pricing-efficiency-and-inefficiency/</guid>
      <description>Question: Do you make money by algorithmic trading, is what Paul Sutton said true?
Answer: By Tom Costello
(https://www.quora.com/Do-you-make-money-by-algorithmic-trading-is-what-Paul-Sutton-said-true
For the largest part I’d have to agree with Paul’s conclusion. His research is more directly empirical, but is completely consistent with my theory on how markets work, and their evolution over time. There isn’t any way I can think of for the typical individual stock trader to pursue ‘algorithmic trading’ in a manner that will lead to greater profit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
